Academic Planning and Development, Office of the Vice President for; Records ua316
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Office of the Vice President for Academic Planning and Development, Records
1978-1987
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Vice President for Academic Planning and Development
ua316
3.0 cubic ft.
This collection is made up of materials related to the changes that took place at the University At Albany in the mid-1980s across the uptown and downtown campuses. This included a reorganization of the library and integration of new digital systems.
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection is arranged in the original order it was recieved in.
Administrative History
The Vice President for Academic Planning and Development oversaw changes to the overall program offered at the University at Albany in the mid-1980s. John W. Shumaker was the Vice President for Academic Planning and Development. He worked for SUNY Albany from 1977 to 1987, first as the Dean of the Humanities and Fine Arts before being promoted to Vice President. During this time the University sought to become more supportive of research being done on campus. Two separate programs were committed to. One was to expand the library’s holdings and become more of a research library. This also meant expanding the variety of the library’s holdings to support new programs such as Asian or African Studies. Included with these materials are plans from SUNY Binghamton who the University at Albany used as a model to develop their new library. The other was to support research programs in the sciences. More resources were put towards supporting work being done for outside institutions. The goal was to connect faculty and students to investors looking to support new research. This was described as being a response to the growth of support in entrepreneurial ventures during the 1980s. This, like the library development, was part of a SUNY wide initiative. The last major program represented in this collection is related to the development of the SUNY Albany program for incoming freshman students. This was in response to a changing view on how students experience college and also the reasons for attending college. The Vice President supported the idea of changing the experience of first year students in the wake of a changing world. Like the other proposals there was a committee created to investigate these proposed changes.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Scope and Contents
This collection has materials created by the Office of the Vice President for Academic Planning and Development. It consists of correspondence, reports from committees created by the Vice President, reports created by other universities, meeting minutes written by committees, and five year plans crafted for the university. These materials cover various topics such as expansion of the academic and social program on campus, introduction of new technology made available to students, as well as an expansion of research initiatives across the University.
Library catalogs -- Automation; School budgets; UAlbany University Development; Research libraries; Educational planning
- Carillon Sheet Music, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Academic Planning, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Academic Planning & Dev. Admin. Overview Presentation Transparencies, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Administrative Systems Advisory Council (ASAC), 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Annenberg, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bernard Arbit Endowment, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Asst. to V.P. for Int'l. Dev., 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Reynold Bloom, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Ray Bromley, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Budget, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Budget, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Budget, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- David Carpenter (Dean Public Health Services), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- China, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Commencement Symposium, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Commencement Symposium, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Computer RFP, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Computer RFP, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Computer RFP, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Equipment Maintenance Charges, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- First Year Experience, Study Committee, 1985-1986 February (Box 1, Folder 21)
- First Year Experience, Study Committee, 1986 March (Box 1, Folder 22)
- First Year Experience, Study Committee, 1986 April-1987 January (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Five Center Managing Committee, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Five Center Managing Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Five Year Plan, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Five Year Plan, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Five Year Plan, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Five Year Plan Review/Update Misc, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Francine Frank (Correspondence), 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- French in Action Series, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Freshman Seminar Program - Evaluation, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Freshman Seminar Program - Administration, 1986 July-1986 December (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Freshman Seminar Program - Administration, 1986 April-1986 July (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Freshman Seminar Program Publicity, Brochures, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Freshman Seminar Program Package, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Freshman Year Experience, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Freshman Year Experience, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Freshman Year Experience, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- General Studies, Director of - Search Committee, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Richard Halsey, 1985; 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Harry Hamilton, 1985; 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Handicapped Education Project, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- High Schools, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Intensive English Language Program Albany, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Intensive English Language Program Albany + Review, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- IELP - Elsewhere, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Professional Development and Quality of Working Life (PDQWL), 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- PDQWL - General Information, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- PDQWL - Proposals, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- PDQWL - Study Leave Reports, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Maria Rudden, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Research + Development Center, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Special Parking Floaters, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Teacher Center, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Test of English as a Foreign Language (TOEFL), 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- US - Asia Institute, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- United University Professionals, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Master Plan Executive Summary, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Chasing the Future: Creating a New Learning Environment for the 21st Century. A Strategic Plan for the University at Albany SUNY. Includes 1992 Mission Statement, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Automation, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Blueprints, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Center for Research Libraries, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Center for Research Libraries, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Collection Development Advisory Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Library Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Library Correspondence, 1982-1983 April (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Library Correspondence, 1983 July-1984 August (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Library Correspondence, 1985 March-1985 December (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Library Correspondence, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Library Correspondence, 1987 January-1987 March (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Library Correspondence, 1987 April (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Library Correspondence, 1987 May-1987 July (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Library Council, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Library Council, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Library Council, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Library Workload Indicators/ Staff Resources, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Research Libraries Committee (Folder 1) (Collection Development Policies: Albany, Binghamton), 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Research Libraries Committee (Folder 2) (Collection Development Policies: Buffalo), 1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Research Libraries Group/ RLIN Membership (Background Reprints on Network), 1978; 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Research Libraries Group/ RLIN Membership, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Research Libraries Group/ RLIN Membership, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Research Libraries Group (RLG)/ RLIN Membership, 1983-1984; 1986 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- School of Information and Library Science Transferred from Office of the Director of the University Libraries, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)